hi spring fans so today is in today's
嗨，春季球迷，所以今天就在今天
installment we're gonna look at JT now
分期付款，我们现在来看一下JT
JT is a Java transaction API it's a way
JT是一种Java事务API，它是一种
of managing distributed transactions
分布式交易的管理
across the transactional resources it is
整个交易资源
the client-side middleware the
客户端中间件
client-side binding for it's called the
客户端绑定称为
Java transaction API or rather as the
Java事务API或更确切地说
X open protocol now the X open protocol
X开放协议现在X开放协议
is a is a protocol that allows different
是一种允许不同的协议
transactional resources to enlist in a
交易资源以争取
transaction by a client initiated by a
由客户发起的交易
client and then to then prepare for that
客户，然后为此做准备
transaction and then upon you know the
交易，然后您知道
sort of signal to then commit or
信号然后提交或
rollback
回滚
this requires naturally necessarily it
这自然需要
requires state that kept external to
需要保持在外部的状态
these transactional resources so you've
这些交易资源，所以您已经
got the cost of synchronizing to
得到了同步到
different otherwise sort of
不一样的
independently moving independently
独立移动
advancing entities in lockstep and
步调一致地推进实体和
you've got this third resource that you
你有第三种资源
have to add to the transaction so as a
必须添加到交易中
result distributions actions can be very
结果分配动作可能非常
slow but that said there are a lot of
慢，但是那有很多
applications that are sort of built
内置的应用程序
yesteryear that and they tend to take
去年，他们倾向于
advantage of these distribute
这些优势的分布
transactions and they people wonder
交易，他们想知道
about whether it's easy enough to use it
关于它是否足够容易使用
use this inside of us instead of a
在我们内部使用这个代替
spring application so certainly it is I
春天的申请，所以肯定是我
don't recommend it though there are a
尽管有一个
lot of ways to solve the problem of
解决问题的方法很多
getting to different resources to
获得不同的资源
different separate independently
分别独立
deployed resources to agree upon
部署资源以达成共识
distribute state that are more elegant
分配更优雅的状态
than JTA but if you happen to have an
比JTA好，但是如果您碰巧有一个
app that's using JTA that's probably not
使用JTA的应用程序可能不是
the answer you want to hear so what I'm
你想听到的答案，所以我是
gonna show you how to do today is how to
今天要告诉你怎么做
take advantage of JTA as its as is
充分利用JTA
supported inside of a instead of spring
支撑在弹簧内部
and in spring boot in particular so I'm
特别是在 spring boot 中
gonna look at two examples two great
要看两个例子，两个很棒
quick examples the first example will be
快速示例，第一个示例是
a spring would application that worked
春天会工作的应用程序
with a data source and a message queue
有数据源和消息队列
so I'm gonna say XA D s and Q and we're
所以我要说XA D和Q，我们
gonna use spring support for building
要用弹簧支撑来建造
web applications we use h2 the in-memory
我们在内存中使用H2的Web应用程序
embedded sequel database we're gonna use
我们将使用的嵌入式续集数据库
ActiveMQ which is an you know a message
ActiveMQ是您知道的消息
broker we use JDBC support and then then
代理，我们使用JDBC支持，然后
you know that'll be the beginning of the
你知道那将是
application but we need in order for
应用程序，但我们需要
this to be a ajt application we need JTA
这是一个ajt应用程序，我们需要JTA
now this is for I think a lot of people
现在这是因为我想很多人
get confused
困惑了
is a specification it describes an API
是描述API的规范
the API requires an implementation when
API需要实现时
people think about that implementation
人们考虑实施
they think about they typically think
他们思考他们通常认为
about consuming what is called a user
关于消费所谓的用户
transaction object and so in the JTA
JTA中的事务对象等
specification there are two key objects
规范中有两个关键对象
a user transaction is meant to be a sort
用户交易本应是一种
of client-side representation of a
的客户端表示形式
transaction manager that is provided by
提供的交易管理器
the JT implementation the client-side
客户端的JT实现
representation has your you know your
代表有你你知道你的
sort of everyday methods for managing
日常管理方法
the body of work of the Union of work in
工作联盟的工作机构
a distributed transaction the start-stop
分布式交易的起止
commits rollback that kind of stuff
提交回滚这类东西
but this is not all that most
但这还不是全部
transaction managers are capable of
交易经理有能力
indeed most transaction managers also
实际上，大多数交易经理也
can go a step further and they can do
可以走得更远，他们可以做到
things like transaction initialization
事务初始化之类的东西
and resumption and suspension right so
并恢复和暂停，这样
you can so you can do more than what's
您可以做到，您不仅可以做更多的事情
exposed on that user transaction
在该用户交易中暴露
interface those extra capabilities are
接口那些额外的功能是
often found in the JTA spec transaction
通常在JTA规范交易中找到
manner manager interface now this this
方式管理器界面现在这个
is a separate interface in Java EE the
是Java EE中的单独接口
the the application server must provide
应用程序服务器必须提供
a user transaction implementation in a
用户交易的实现
well under well-known J&amp;A location there
在著名的J＆A地点下
is no requirement to provide a well
不需要提供井
known transaction manager implementation
已知的事务管理器实现
but in practice most application servers
但实际上大多数应用程序服务器
do provide an implementation it's just
确实提供了一个实现
not under the same portable sort of JD
不在同一种便携式JD下
and location but spring knows about all
和位置，但春天知道所有
the common locations and it will take
常见的位置，这将需要
advantage of both you know the one that
两者的优势你们都知道
has the most power it'll it'll use that
具有最大的力量，它将使用
if it can right so what we're gonna use
如果可以的话，我们将使用什么
what we're gonna do is we're gonna use
我们要做的是使用
our own standalone JTA implementation
我们自己的独立JTA实现
again spring doesn't care if the beans
再次春天不在乎豆子
that it needs the objects of type
它需要类型的对象
transaction manager and of type user
事务管理器和用户类型
transaction come from a Jane di context
交易来自Jane di上下文
in an application server or if they come
在应用程序服务器中，或者如果它们来了
from a sort of standalone JTA
来自一种独立的JTA
implementation that spring boot
spring boot 的实现
automatically configures for us what
自动为我们配置
we're going to do is we're going to
我们要做的是
configure JTA in our Springwood
在我们的Springwood中配置JTA
application or rather we own that spring
应用程序，或者说我们拥有那个春天
boot configure JTA for us right now
引导为我们立即配置JTA
if we ran spring and the spring would
如果我们跑春天，春天会
application inside of
内部的应用
application server on java application
Java应用程序上的应用程序服务器
server the minority use case to be sure
确保少数用例
but just in case that is your use case
但以防万一这是您的用例
this will just automatically work you
这将自动为您工作
don't even need a standalone
甚至不需要独立
implementation it'll detect the jndi
实现它将检测到jndi
types on the application server and
应用服务器上的类型
it'll configure the wrap and adapt those
它将配置包装并调整那些
transactional resources if they
交易资源，如果他们
implement the XA they required XA
实施他们需要的XA XA
interfaces right so there's a X a
正确的接口，所以有一个X
resource interface inside of JTA and in
JTA内部和内部的资源接口
the JMS world the java api for messaging
JMS世界中用于消息传递的Java api
there's the X a connection factory which
有一个X连接工厂
is a JMS connection factor that
是一个JMS连接因子，
implements the XA resource contract and
实施XA资源合同，并
then in the JBC rule there's an X a data
然后在JBC规则中有一个X a数据
source which is a data source that
源是一个数据源
implements the X a contract so as long
只要执行X合约
as you're using Jane di provisioned you
当您使用Jane di设置您时
know connection factors and message
了解连接因素和消息
queues and so on and the Springwood
排队等，还有斯普林伍德
auto-configuration will will use the the
自动配置将使用
JT transaction manager as it's bound
绑定的JT交易管理器
inside of the jndi directory in your
在您的jndi目录中
application server in our case though
虽然在我们的例子中是应用服务器
we're not using a java application
我们没有使用Java应用程序
server we're just guessing a local sort
服务器，我们只是在猜测本地排序
of a embedded sprinkler application so
嵌入式喷头的应用
we're gonna use an we're gonna have
我们将使用一个
spring boot auto configure a JTA
Spring Boot自动配置JTA
implementation for us and spring boot
对我们的实现和spring boot
out-of-the-box supports three very
开箱即用的支持三个
popular very widely used choices here
流行的非常广泛使用的选择
atomic host and boot Onix both of which
原子主机和启动Onix两者
are Apache 2 license to open source etc
是Apache 2开放源代码的许可证等
they're both actually you know
他们俩其实你都知道
interestingly both they originated from
有趣的是，它们都起源于
Belgium a little a little bit of trivia
比利时有点琐事
their atomic O's is I think we're gonna
他们的原子O是我认为我们要
use that not because it's better or
使用它不是因为更好
worse or anything but because it starts
更糟或什么，但因为它开始
with a one thing you should know about
你应该知道的一件事
atomic host is that it also has a
原子主机是它也有一个
premier sort of level right so you can
最高级的权利，所以你可以
use the open source JTA stuff and that
使用开源JTA的东西
works just fine
效果很好
but if you want to if want to go beyond
但是如果你想超越
JTA and handle some more interesting
JTA并处理一些更有趣的事情
corner cases in the JTA world the folks
JTA世界中的极端案例
behind the Tama Coast cell you know
在多摩海岸牢房后面
supported enterprise grade extras okay
支持的企业级附加功能还可以
all right
好吧
so we're gonna hit generate and because
所以我们要点击generate，因为
this is spring boot both of our both our
这是我们两个人的 spring boot
data source and our message queue will
数据源和我们的消息队列将
be
是
automatically configured for us in fact
实际上自动为我们配置
will be embedded there's no reason we
将被嵌入，没有理由我们
couldn't specify property is that point
无法指定属性就是这一点
to stand alone separate you know data
单独知道数据
sources and and message queues running
源和消息队列正在运行
out of process but in our case we don't
过时了，但在我们这里我们不会
really need to we're just trying to to
真的需要我们只是试图
get an example going so they're gonna be
得到一个例子，所以他们会
automatically created for us and
自动为我们创建的
configured for us in the spring good
在春季为我们配置好
application we're gonna go here we're
应用程序，我们要去这里，我们
gonna create a application that it has a
将创建一个具有
rest controller so we'll save public
rest controller ，这样我们就可以保存公共信息
static class X a rest controller okay
静态类X的 rest controller 可以
maybe X a API rest controller and we're
也许X是API rest控制器，我们
gonna make this a risk controller like
会让它成为风险控制者，例如
so and in the rest control room and have
所以，在休息控制室，并有
a write method that takes as its payload
以其有效负载为单位的写方法
a map of string and we'll call that the
字符串映射，我们称其为
payload this will just be a wrapper for
有效载荷，这将只是一个包装
a JSON object that'll be sent for the
一个将为
client and we want to make this a at
客户，我们想在这里
post mapping so somebody's gonna write
发布地图，以便有人去写
right to the message queue here and we
到这里的消息队列，我们
want to be able to throw an exception if
希望能够在以下情况下引发异常
some if something should go wrong so
一些如果应该出问题的话
here we're gonna say request per am
在这里，我们要说请求
optional so it either it's gonna be
可选的，所以它将成为
there or it won't be and if it's not
那里或者不会，如果不是
there then we're gonna be able to you
那我们就可以给你
know handle that case gracefully without
知道优雅地处理这种情况
a lot of if if normal checks okay so
如果正常检查的话很多
what we're gonna do is we're going to
我们要做的是
use the auto configure JMS template okay
使用自动配置JMS模板好吗
this is the client-side interface for
这是客户端的接口
working with JMS I'm gonna use the
与JMS合作，我将使用
automatically configured JDBC template
自动配置的JDBC模板
okay
好的
provide those in the constructor here
在这里提供构造函数中的那些
spring boot automatically configures
Spring Boot自动配置
them we're just injecting them to use
他们我们只是注入他们使用
them and we're going to send messages
他们，我们将要发送消息
what we're gonna do is going to send a
我们要做的就是发送一个
message to a JMS destination here called
消息到这里的JMS目标
I'll just give it a variable name here
我只给它一个变量名
to make it easy to remember so we're
为了容易记住，所以我们
gonna call it messages and we will write
将其称为消息，我们将写
them messages to the database and we'll
他们将消息发送到数据库，我们将
write it to a message queue and if we
将其写入消息队列，如果我们
need to so but let's see we're gonna say
需要这样做，但让我们看看我们要说的是
this dot jvc template dot X actually
这个点jvc模板实际上是点X
cute insert into message-id
可爱地插入message-id
and we're gonna call it ID and we're
我们将其称为ID，
gonna call it message I guess that'll be
要称呼它，我想那会是
fine
精细
values question mark question mark and
值问号问号和
we'll pass in a a ID here and the ID
我们将在此处传递一个ID和ID
well in a record for later so we'll say
好在以后的记录中，所以我们说
ID equals u u ID dot random string to
ID等于uu ID点随机字符串
string okay and well pass in a message
字符串还可以，并顺利传递消息
here and the message will be derived
在这里，消息将被导出
from the payload of the JSON body so
从JSON主体的有效负载中
we'll say request or payload dot get
我们会说请求或有效负载点得到
name string message equals hello name
名称字符串消息等于您好名称
okay so there's the message that we're
好，所以有消息说我们
gonna send update will work there we go
要发送更新将在那里工作
and we want to send a message via the
我们想通过发送消息
JMS template as well so we'll say this
还有JMS模板，所以我们这样说
dot JMS template JMS template dot
点JMS模板JMS模板点
convert and send and what we do is we
转换并发送，我们要做的是
gonna send a message to a destination
要发送消息到目的地
called destination and the message will
称为目的地，消息将
be this right there we go
我们就在这里吗
so we're gonna send the net the message
所以我们要向网络发送消息
we're gonna write it to the Davis and
我们要写给戴维斯
I'm going to send an event or publish a
我要发送事件或发布
message into the broker or some other
消息传递给经纪人或其他
component running in the same node or
在同一节点中运行的组件或
running in another node could then
然后在另一个节点上运行
receive it and so let's do that now as
收到它，所以现在就开始做吧
well let's create another component here
好吧，我们在这里创建另一个组件
Jamis listener public static class
Jamis侦听器公共静态类
message notification listener and here
消息通知侦听器和此处
well you know this is a service and
好吧，您知道这是一项服务，
we'll just declared lis respond to on
我们只是宣布lis回应
new message right and the payload will
新消息权，有效负载将
be the message itself or maybe we could
是消息本身，或者我们可以
just write the ID right week I should
只要在正确的星期写身份证
just send the idea of the record that
只是发送记录的想法
was written the claim check pad on there
被写在那里的索赔检查垫
as long as they have the idea we can
只要他们有我们的想法
look it up again later so
以后再查一下
i d-- and we're gonna use a nice feature
我会-我们将使用一个不错的功能
here and one of the more recent versions
在这里和最新版本之一
of spring which is a JMS listener
春天的一个JMS侦听器
annotation i think this is spring
注解，我认为这是春天
framework for that too but you know
框架也可以，但是你知道
memory might might be failing pair and
内存可能配对失败，并且
all I'm gonna do is I'm gonna print out
我要做的就是打印出来
the new message so message ID okay now
新消息，所以消息ID可以了
this Jamis listener annotation is a
这个Jamis侦听器注释是一个
convenient ships in textual cut for
方便的船在文本切割
creating a message of this inner
创造这种内在的信息
container so again you if you ever use a
容器，如果您曾经使用过
message listen container or from message
消息监听容器或来自消息
driven bean this is just far more
带动的豆，这远不止于此
convenient there's similar support
方便有类似的支持
inside of the spring AMQP for the mqp
在MQP的春季AMQP内部
listeners there's some other support and
听众还有其他支持，
other spring projects but suffice it to
其他春季项目，但足以满足
say we've got everything we need there
说我们在那里有我们需要的一切
okay so I think the last thing that
好吧，我想最后一件事
we've been would be very convenient to
我们去过会很方便
look at is a way to enumerate any
看是一种枚举任何
messages in the database wouldn't that
数据库中的消息不会那样
be useful that might be useful let's
可能有用，让我们
let's see about that so we're gonna say
让我们来看看，所以我们要说
get mapping public and we're gonna
公开绘制地图，我们将
create a map a collection of maps of
创建一个地图，该地图的集合
strings messages or just call it we'd
留言或直接给我们打电话
okay and we'll save return this thought
好的，我们将保存此想法
JBC template dot query select all from
JBC模板点查询全选
message new row mapper okay so we're
消息新行映射器好，所以我们
just getting a classic you know JBC
刚获得经典，您知道JBC
template
模板
query and we're gonna say for every
查询，我们将为每个
result that comes back let's create a
返回的结果让我们创建一个
map a hash map here and we're gonna put
在这里映射一个哈希映射，我们将把
some fields in there we're gonna say ID
那里的一些字段我们会说ID
equals alright result set duck get
等于结果集鸭子得到
string ID and I will say this old set
字符串ID，我会说这个旧集
dead get string message okay
死得到字符串消息好
there's this now of course you're
现在当然有这个
looking at this as I am and seeing a
看着我，看到一个
lots of opportunities to remove dead
清除死者的机会很多
code so let's get rid of that we don't
代码，让我们摆脱它，我们不
need it this can be a lambda that's nice
需要它可以是一个很好的lambda
as well so good good good and there we
很好，很好，很好，在那里
go so that's our read endpoint right so
走，那是我们的读取端点，所以
the final thing that we need to care
我们需要关心的最后一件事
about is rolling back the transaction if
大约在回滚交易，如果
we were you know to demonstrate that
我们知道你要证明
this does it does as we expect so let's
做到了我们所期望的，所以让我们
make this a transactional endpoint so
使其成为交易端点
I'm gonna say a transactional using
我要说的是交易式
Springs a transactional annotation there
在此弹出事务注释
you might have seen javac stub
您可能已经看过javac存根
transactions at transactional that's a
交易的交易是
new feature in Java EE 7 released in
Java EE 7中的新功能发布于
whereas the spring transactional
而春季交易
annotation covers a superset of the
注释涵盖了的超集
support there and of course it's been
支持那里，当然
around for you know 12 12 years or so 10
大约你知道12 12年10
years at least
至少几年
so we'll say if rollback dot or else is
所以我们会说如果回滚点否则
equal to false throw new run time
等于错误抛出新的运行时间
exception ok couldn't write the message
好的确定无法写消息
okay there we are so those are our
好吧，我们在那里，所以那是我们的
messages we've written them and that
我们已经写过的消息
should do let's go ahead and see if that
应该做吧，看看是否
works let's go ahead and configure this
工作，让我们继续进行配置
now again what's gonna happen is it's
现在又会发生的是
gonna create a JMS connection factory
要创建一个JMS连接工厂
image and JBC data source spring is
图像和JBC数据源是
gonna see that both beans implement the
会看到两个豆都实现了
XA resource type somewhere along the
XA资源类型
line so that'll make them a candidate
行，以便使他们成为候选人
for enlistment in the XA transaction the
参与XA交易
auto configuration will wrap them and
自动配置会将它们包装起来，
adapt them for the atomic host types so
使它们适应原子宿主类型，以便
we'll actually the data source that gets
我们将实际获得的数据源
created will actually be a atomic host
创建的实际上是一个原子宿主
data source that wraps our x8 data
包装x8数据的数据源
source and there'll be an atomic close
源，并且将有原子关闭
connection factor that wraps our X a
包装X的连接因子
connection factory now what you see on
连接工厂现在您所看到的
the console here is the is the polar you
控制台在这里是极地
know the sort of heartbeat that gets
知道那种心跳
created by the messages per container
由每个容器的消息创建
you know cycling all the time so let's
你一直都在骑自行车，所以让我们
see here
看这里
terminal and what data did we say we're
终端，我们说了什么数据
gonna right we're gonna say we said that
对，我们要说我们说
we're gonna write based on the name
我们要根据名字写
right so that's a
对，所以这是一个
go to the console here and we're gonna
去这里的控制台，我们要
send a curl with the name equals spring
发一个卷发，名字等于春天
fans it's gonna have content type F
粉丝，它将拥有内容类型F
equals application JSON and we're gonna
等于应用程序JSON，我们将
send it to this endpoint we're not gonna
发送到这个端点，我们不会
trigger an exception yet so I'm gonna
触发一个异常，所以我要
send it so there we don't have the table
发送它，所以我们没有桌子
all right so we need that tape my
好的，所以我们需要那个胶带
mistake so we'll go here create a table
错误，所以我们将在这里创建表
and the schema here scheme or ASCII data
以及此处的架构方案或ASCII数据
schema dot sequel create table message
模式点续集创建表消息
okay and it will be ID VAR car 255 not
好吧，那将是ID VAR car 255 not
null unique and message bar car 255 not
空唯一性和消息栏汽车255不
know okay try that again
知道可以再试一次
okay right localhost
好吧，本地主机
there's the read we've got one message
在阅读中，我们只有一条信息
you know let's do another one just to
你知道让我们再做一个
confirm so we're gonna send now hello
确认，我们将立即发送你好
spring fans hello again spring fans send
春季粉丝们你好再次春季粉丝们送
we've got now two messages right there's
我们现在有两个消息
this one here and the hell of spring
这一个在这里和春天的地狱
fans
粉丝
now let's trigger an exception right so
现在让我们触发一个异常吧
you know and if we look on the console
你知道，如果我们在控制台上看
also here we should see you know message
也在这里我们应该看到你知道的消息
ID only twice alright so there it is it
身份证只有两次就可以了
says two matches right there my two
说两个比赛，我的两个
matches that means it's it's you know
匹配意味着这就是你知道的
the message has been sent twice and we
邮件已发送两次，我们
see on the console that you know we see
在控制台上看到您知道我们看到的
in the output of the rest Napier that
在其余Napier的输出中
it's been written to the database twice
它已经两次写入数据库
so everything's fine now exception or
所以现在一切都很好，例外
rollback rather equals true I didn't
回滚相当等于true我没有
that what we said so rollback is the
我们所说的回滚是
parameter here yep rollback is equal to
这里的参数是回滚等于
true to the thrown exception
对抛出的异常为真
voila if we go to our end point we
瞧，如果我们走到终点，我们
should see nothing else right didn't get
应该什么都没看到没得到
written after all and if we look on the
毕竟，如果我们看一下
console in the JMS listener here still
JMS侦听器中的控制台仍然在此处
just two matches right you can't see a
只有两场比赛，您看不到
third one so even though we threw the
第三，所以即使我们扔了
exception after seemingly both the Jamis
似乎都是贾米斯之后的例外
template and the JBC template had done
模板和JBC模板已经完成
their work the unit of work hadn't been
他们的工作不是工作单位
committed yet and it was rolled back for
已提交，并且已回退
us automatically so we've used atomic
我们会自动使用，因此我们使用了原子
was to you know correctly enlist both
要知道正确招募这两个人
transactional resources and to roll back
交易资源并回滚
the commit as though they never happened
好像从未发生过的承诺
creating a you know a consistent state
创建一个您知道一致状态的状态
from the outside all right so this is a
从外面好吧，这是一个
simple example here we've got a
一个简单的例子，我们有一个
unambiguous data source and an
明确的数据源和
unambiguous connection factory what if
明确的连接工厂，如果
we had two different data sources right
我们有两个不同的数据源
this would require a little bit more
这将需要更多
work so let's take a let's take a look
工作，让我们来看看
at that as an example well close this
以此为例很好地关闭这个
off close this and go to start spring
关闭关闭并开始春天
nao
o
now let's say we wanted to create a two
现在假设我们要创建两个
data source example not using any kind
数据源示例不使用任何种类
of JMS just two different data sources
JMS只是两个不同的数据源
we use h2 again we're going to use JTA
我们再次使用h2我们将使用JTA
so we use atomic also we use
所以我们使用原子也使用
the web support again we need to JBC
再次需要我们的网络支持
support and I think that will do now in
支持，我认为这将在
this example what we have to do is we
这个例子我们要做的是
have to you know first of all spring
首先要知道
boot is the auto configuration a lot of
开机是自动配置的很多
that is optimized for if we have a
如果我们有一个
in-memory database on a class path then
然后在类路径上创建内存数据库
it'll automatically create a data source
它将自动创建数据源
for us if we don't provide our own data
如果我们不提供自己的数据
source and it doesn't do a great job if
来源，如果做得不好，
we have more than one data source so
我们有多个数据源，因此
let's go ahead and create two days
让我们继续创造两天
sources ourselves here well you know we
在这里很好地了解我们自己，您知道我们
need to do this a little bit more
需要多做一点
manually so in our code we have a few
手动操作，因此在我们的代码中，我们有一些
things that we need to configure out
我们需要配置的东西
first of all what we want to do is want
首先我们想要做的是
to configure the data sources themselves
自行配置数据源
right so we'll say beam data source a ok
对，所以我们说光束数据源还可以
beam data source B data source B ok ok
光束数据源B数据源B好的好的
there's this and a and we need to
有这个和一个，我们需要
provide a implementation of the JDBC
提供JDBC的实现
datasource type that we want in this
我们想要的数据源类型
case I'm going to use the h2 data source
情况下，我将使用h2数据源
type right so JDBC datasource that's
输入正确的，因此JDBC数据源是
this one right here this is on the class
这个就在这上课
path but right now they are the auto
路径，但现在它们是自动的
configured h2 driver is a runtime only
配置的H2驱动程序仅是运行时
so let's make it compile time so we can
因此，让我们使其编译时，以便
see the type and I will say new equals
看到类型，我会说新的等于
this set URL equals what we want what is
这个设置的URL等于我们想要的是什么
the URL for that and it's h2 in memory
URL，它是内存中的h2
string examples good
字符串示例很好
quick start to find we use this and I
快速开始找到我们使用这个，我
don't want this to be the same file each
不想每个都是相同的文件
time so I'll just localize it you will
时间，所以我将其本地化，您将
override the string here so I'll say B
在这里覆盖字符串，所以我说B
plus a random string hew ID dot and I'm
再加上一个随机的字符串hew ID点，我是
done there we go okay
在那里完成，我们可以
actually I'll probably be fine if we
实际上，如果我们
just leave it like that okay so we're
就这样离开吧，所以我们
going to create an in-memory database
将要创建一个内存数据库
that is named by the data source would
由数据源命名的
be called a and B the username will be
被称为A和B，用户名将为
si the password is empty turn that like
si密码是空转那
so okay so we've got now two of them
好吧，我们现在有两个
data sources we need to initialize the
数据源，我们需要初始化
data right so again these are two
正确的数据，所以这又是两个
different data sources this this one
这是不同的数据源
could be my sequel one could be post
可能是我的续集，可能会发布
Chris it just happens that they're both
克里斯碰巧他们俩
data sources that are you know the same
您知道的数据源相同
type in this case but they don't need to
在这种情况下键入，但他们不需要
be right the one could be Oracle one it
是的，可能是甲骨文之一
could be post cuts who cares what we
可能是削减人员谁在乎我们
want to do is want to initialize the
想做的就是想初始化
data and both of them right we don't
数据，而且两者都正确，我们不这样做
want to bring boot to run its own
想要带开机自行运行
initializer we want to create our own
我们要创建自己的初始化程序
initializer that that contributes to
有助于
custom data maybe one will have a table
定制数据也许会有一张桌子
full of pets you know objects with names
充满宠物，您知道带有名字的物体
and another one will have a table full
另一个将有一张满的桌子
of messages the same ideas before so
消息之前有相同的想法
we'll create a beam of type of data
我们将创建一束数据类型
source initializer a in it when I return
我返回时在其中的源初始化
in it we need to provide a data source
我们需要提供一个数据源
the the data source that we need here so
我们在这里需要的数据源
there's this okay I'm gonna use a call
可以，我要打个电话
it a as well and or just create that
它也是，或者只是创建那个
init method
初始化方法
good and we'll create a data source of
好，我们将创建一个数据源
initializer now data source initializer
现在是初始化器数据源初始化器
is a convenient type in spring itself
是弹簧本身的一种方便类型
that you know you can use just for that
你知道你可以用它
you can use to initialize databases so
您可以用来初始化数据库，以便
here is our data source and we're going
这是我们的数据源，我们要
to create a database populating we're
创建一个填充我们的数据库
going to use a resource database
将使用资源数据库
Popular's and the resource database
大众资源数据库
popular is going to need a new class
流行将需要一个新的班级
path resource and we're going to say
路径资源，我们要说的是
name dot of a sequel you know on top
在顶部知道续集的名称点
sequel and then that'll do I think
续集，那我想
that'll give us a lot I think right
我认为这会给我们很多
there right so good now we need to run
那里很好，现在我们需要运行
two of these init methods so one for the
其中有两种init方法，一种用于
a database or another one for the B
B的一个数据库或另一个数据库
database okay
数据库还可以
good there we are there's the two data
很好，我们有两个数据
sources and the two initializers and
源和两个初始化器和
that should be enough we need to disable
这应该足够了，我们需要禁用
our default initializer all right and we
我们默认的初始化程序好了，我们
need to create some schema here as
需要在这里创建一些架构
before so we'll create a two different
在此之前，我们将创建两个不同的
tables one called a dot sequel hey dad
表一叫点续集嘿爸爸
sequel contains our table of pets okay
续集包含我们的宠物表，可以
and nicknames
和昵称
good so there's this and be that sequel
很好所以有续集
will contain the message table and you
将包含消息表，您
know savings before will just write a
知道储蓄之前只会写一个
message to the database okay now then
消息到数据库现在可以了
with that under way we have the two
通过这种方式，我们有两个
initializers and two data sources you
初始化程序和两个数据源
know you might have other things you
知道你可能还有其他事情
want to configure on these data sources
想要在这些数据源上进行配置
right you want to do that in the
对，你想在
properties and you can still do that
属性，您仍然可以这样做
just because we're configuring the base
只是因为我们正在配置基础
object or not and code here doesn't mean
是否对象，此处的代码并不意味着
you couldn't and configuration
你不能和配置
properties you know prefix equals a so
您知道前缀的属性等于so
that way if you went to a your
这样，如果您去了
configuration file or rather that would
配置文件，或者那样
be I guess to enter config configuration
我猜想进入配置配置
file both both would take a properties
两者都将具有属性
right you could say a dot a dot well and
对，你可以说一个点一个点，
your property that the JDBC datasource
您的属性，即JDBC数据源
type here supports would be then
在这里输入支持将是
directly referential so it ain't out URL
直接引用，因此不会出现URL
a dot whatever I'm just doing it in code
我在代码中所做的任何一个点
because it's a simple example but take
因为这是一个简单的例子，但是
take note you could do that absolutely
请注意，您绝对可以这样做
all right so we've got two different
好吧，我们有两个不同
data sources so we've got two different
数据源，所以我们有两个不同的
initializers let's go ahead and create a
初始化程序让我们继续创建一个
rest endpoint just a you know we want to
其余端点只是一个您知道我们想要
write data to both endpoints into twelve
将两个端点的数据写入十二个
databases so we're gonna say public
数据库，所以我们要公开
static class let's get rid of this thing
静态类让我们摆脱这件事
here pause that XA d you know XA i'm api
在这里暂停XA，您知道XA是api吗？
rest controller call this a rest
rest controller 称此为休息
controller public void right
控权人公共无效权
and what do we want to do we're gonna
我们要做什么
send it post and just like last time we
发送它的帖子，就像我们上一次一样
want this to be transactional right so
希望这是交易权利，所以
we'll say at transactional and the
我们将在交易型和
request body will be just like last time
请求正文将与上次相同
a map of string of string payload okay
字符串有效负载的字符串映射可以
and we're gonna optionally throw an
而且我们可以选择扔一个
exception if there is a parameter there
如果那里有参数则异常
so we'll say optional boolean rollback
所以我们说可选的布尔回滚
okay and now we need to use the
好的，现在我们需要使用
different data sources here to create
在这里创建不同的数据源
jvc yeah you know JP templates we don't
jvc是的，您知道我们不知道的JP模板
have two different JDBC templates so we
有两个不同的JDBC模板，所以我们
need to create them ourselves so I will
需要自己创建它们，所以我会
say JB's template a and B okay I'll
说JB的模板a和B好吧，我会
provide those two in terms of data
提供这两个数据
sources here so provide the two
此处提供两个来源
different data sources here in the
这里的不同数据源
constructor and just initialize a new
构造函数，然后初始化一个新的
JBC template a new JBC template B and
JBC模板，新的JBC模板B和
voila okay now we can do a work so the a
瞧，现在我们可以开始工作了，所以
to the aid database has the table for
到援助数据库的表
the for the pets so we'll say this dot a
的宠物，所以我们说这个点
dot execute or update rather insert into
点执行或更新，而不是插入
pet ID nick name values question mark
宠物ID昵称值问号
question mark and we'll take the name
问号，我们取这个名字
here so string name equals payload dot
这里的字符串名称等于有效负载点
get name string message equals hello
获取名称字符串消息等于你好
name and we're gonna write the name into
名称，我们将名称写入
the database here we'll say that we have
这里的数据库，我们说我们有
an ID you know ID that too
您也知道ID的ID
bring a random string okay name there's
带一个随机的字符串好名字
this and then in the B database we want
然后在B数据库中
to say insert into message message and
说插入消息中，并且
we'll pass in this message here voila
我们将在此处传递此消息
okay so that'll be fine and then of
好，这样就可以了，然后
course just as with last time I want to
当然和上次一样
say if we'll back dot or else so if it's
告诉我们是否要返回点，否则
false or if it's not there then we won't
错误或如果不存在，那么我们不会
bother but if it is there then and if
麻烦，但如果它在那里，如果
it's true then we're gonna throw a
是的，那我们要扔一个
runtime exception couldn't write the
运行时异常无法编写
data to the databases okay voila
数据到数据库好了，瞧
okay that should do it it's a
好的，应该这样做
transactional endpoint just as before
交易端点与以前一样
except now instead of using JMS and and
除了现在，而不是使用JMS和
JDBC we're using just JDBC we've got a
JDBC我们仅使用JDBC，
payload we're going to send JSON of type
我们将发送类型为JSON的有效负载
name or with value of type name the a
名称或具有名称类型的值a
thoughts equals four pets the B dot
想法等于四个宠物的B点
sequel is four messages we should have
续集是我们应该拥有的四个信息
some way to confirm that this was done
某种方式确认已完成
shouldn't my so let's create two
我不应该，所以让我们创建两个
endpoints here to read the data so we'll
此处读取数据的端点，因此我们将
say two endpoints of type the collection
说出集合类型的两个端点
of map of string pets okay and we'll say
串宠物的地图还可以，我们会说
I could get mapping pets I'm gonna
我可以得到要映射的宠物
simply return this dot a dot query
只需将此点返回一个点查询
select all from pet new row mapper and I
从pet new row mapper中全选，然后我
don't even need that do way we can just
甚至不需要这样做，我们就可以
make it a little simpler just a
使它简单一点
collection of strings
字符串集合
the turn results that got get string
获得转弯的转弯结果
nick name perfect for lambda okay there
昵称非常适合lambda，好吗
we are
我们是
there's our simple pets endpoint and
这是我们的简单宠物端点，
create another one for messages here
在此处为消息创建另一个
message and get the message all right
消息并正确接收消息
that should allow us to confirm that
那应该让我们确认
everything is working you know we'll
一切正常，你知道我们会的
have the visible side effects on the
对...有明显的副作用
outside so we can prove you know we can
在外面，所以我们可以证明你知道我们可以
see that only what we expect to have
看到只有我们期望的
happened has actually happened now what
发生了实际上发生了什么
is wrong or get our JBC URL isn't
错误或获取我们的JBC URL不正确
correct for the file type so we can say
正确的文件类型，所以我们可以说
just store it in the local file system
只需将其存储在本地文件系统中
in the same directory as the one that's
在与该目录相同的目录中
running this process okay it's up and
运行这个程序好了
running so curl a name hello spring fans
跑步如此卷曲一个名字你好春季球迷
same as before except a slightly
除略有改变外，其他与之前相同
different we're not gonna roll this one
不同的是我们不会推出这一
back not yet anyway right insert into
反正还没有插入
message table message not found that's
找不到消息表消息
because I forgot to make this is the B
因为我忘了让这个是B
data source remember they're two
数据源记住他们是两个
different things
不同的东西
so well we start again where we start
好吧，我们从头开始
delete the data from
从中删除数据
here
这里
okay
好的
- a message not found
-找不到消息
okay oh sorry God be be now
好吧，对不起上帝现在
to be to be more explicit you might have
更明确地说，你可能有
used a qualifier I could have used a
我可以用一个限定词
qualifier like that but in this case the
这样的限定词，但在这种情况下
name well automatically you know the
自动命名，你知道
name of the variable will disambiguate
变量名称将消除歧义
okay that way if you had used a
好的，如果您使用过
qualifier then it wouldn't matter what
预选赛然后什么都没关系
the name of the variable is this is
变量的名称是
exactly the kind of issue you want to
正是您要解决的问题
avoid and of course now this is a
避免，当然现在这是一个
problem so our MRF sorry here get rid of
问题，所以我们的MRF很抱歉在这里摆脱了
all this stuff here goodbye
所有这些东西再见
all right okay good so let's send that
好的，好的，让我们发送
it's working good localhost pets got
运行良好的本地主机宠物
that and messages got that okay so our
那和消息都还好，所以我们
messages and our pets are there as we
信息和我们的宠物在那里
expect everything's fine
期待一切都很好
let's go ahead and send another message
让我们继续发送另一个消息
just to prove that it works again hello
只是为了证明它再次起作用
again
再次
spring fans and again okay so there's
春天的粉丝，再次好吧，所以
that there's that now let's throw an
现在，让我们扔一个
exception so we're gonna send spring
例外，所以我们要送春天
fans again but this time we'll say roll
再次成为粉丝，但这次我们要说“滚”
back equals true and that's the primer
back等于true，这就是入门
that we used right yep roll back so here
我们使用正确的是回滚，所以这里
we go
我们去
ready one two three go throw an
准备一二三去扔
exception we should only see
例外，我们只能看到
did I forget to make this transactional
我忘了让这个交易
ah it's not transactional it is
啊，这不是交易
transactional but what I forgot to do is
事务性的，但我忘了要做的是
wrap the data sources right so this is
正确包装数据源，所以这是
what we need to do this is actually the
我们需要做的实际上是
last missing piece here so we have our
最后遗失的一块在这里，所以我们有
two data sources we have the move
我们有两个数据源
initialize the data quickly the
快速初始化数据
transaction manager that we're using is
我们正在使用的事务管理器是
transactional you know it's a JTA
事务性的，您知道这是一个JTA
transaction manager but it's not aware
交易经理，但不知道
of these transactional resources so the
这些交易资源中的
final thing that we need to do is to to
我们要做的最后一件事是
automatically initialize our data
自动初始化我们的数据
sources and wrap them and we can do that
资源并包装它们，我们可以做到这一点
by injecting here a X a data source
通过在此处向X注入数据源
wrapper into the constructor of our
包装到我们的构造函数中
application and here we say wrapper dot
应用程序，在这里我们说包装点
AB data source equals this throw an
AB数据源等于此抛出一个
exception and do the same thing here
例外，在这里做同样的事情
now these data sources I need to return
现在我需要返回这些数据源
well we can return the type and that
好吧，我们可以返回类型，
should be okay so there's this there we
应该没关系，所以这里有我们
go so we're returning a data source
去吧，我们要返回一个数据源
we're wrapping the data source with a
我们用一个
wrapper and then everything else is
包装器，然后其他所有东西
basically as it was let's go ahead and
基本上就像我们继续
restart okay we set both of them now
重启好吧，我们现在都设置它们
here we go let's try this again this
在这里，我们再尝试一次
time we've done the right thing we've
我们做正确的事的时间
enlisted both data sources in the
列出了两个数据源
transaction by using the data source
使用数据源进行交易
wrapper interface the implementation of
包装器接口的实现
which is provided by the auto
由汽车提供
configuration as you can imagine there
您可以想象的配置
are three different implementations of
是三种不同的实现
this type there's a Tomica line between
这种类型之间有一条Tomica线
a clone in Narayana one right so we're
是Narayana的一个克隆，所以我们
using the one that's provided by our
使用我们提供的
implementation or we're going to send
实施，否则我们将发送
spring fans we're not going to roll it
春天的粉丝们，我们不会滚
back if we go here they're both there
返回，如果我们去这里，他们都在那里
the message and the the pet or the user
消息和宠物或用户
I guess okay pets is probably a poor
我想好的宠物可能是穷人
name for spring fans okay
春季球迷的名字好吗
so there's that now let's roll back the
所以现在让我们回滚
exception okay so exception our rollback
异常好，所以异常我们的回滚
equals rather rather rollback equals
等于而不是回滚等于
true throws an exception one message in
true在一条消息中引发异常
the messages and point one message and
消息并指出一条消息，然后
the pets in point so there we go it did
宠物就是这样，所以我们去了
not write that second registered message
不写第二条注册消息
right we rewrote it to the endpoint it
正确，我们将其重写为端点
certainly got processed but then we
当然得到了处理，但后来我们
threw an exception so the unit of work
引发了异常，因此工作单元
that wrapped both of those was undone
包裹这两个的操作都被撤消了
all right so in this installment of
好的，所以在本期的
spring tips we've looked at how to use
春天的技巧，我们已经研究了如何使用
JTA we've looked at how the underlying
JTA我们已经研究了底层
abstraction plugs in the various
抽象插入各种
relevant pieces from the JTA API for you
来自JTA API的相关文章
be it inside of a Java EE application
在Java EE应用程序内部
server or in a standalone embedded kind
服务器或独立的嵌入式服务器
of fashion we've also looked at how to
关于时尚，我们还研究了如何
work with more than one data source
处理多个数据源
which i think is a very common use case
我认为这是一个非常常见的用例
now that said I do really want to
现在说我真的很想
underscore that this is not a great fit
强调这不是一个很好的选择
for sort of modern applications it
对于某种现代应用
creates a single point of failure it's
造成单点故障
not going to be what you want if you're
如果你是，那将不是你想要的
trying to deal with multiple
试图处理多个
micro-services none of which
微型服务
implement the accepted protocol anyway
仍然执行公认的协议
and it requires a file system and I do
它需要一个文件系统，我可以
mean a Java that I know that file my
是指我知道该文件的Java
transaction managers need a durable file
交易经理需要一个持久的文件
Java dot IO dot file in order to do
Java点IO点文件才能做
their work which is kind of a naive
他们的工作真是天真
assumption because in the world of the
假设，因为在
cloud you can't really take for granted
你真的不能认为云
the presence our availability of a file
存在我们文件的可用性
so it'd be nicer if there was some sort
所以如果有某种更好的选择
of other API
其他API的
besides the Java dot IO dot file which
除了Java点IO点文件之外
is itself final right so you can use
本身就是最终的权利，因此您可以使用
some sort of other durable I'll store
我会存储某种其他耐用性
right all right thank you so much from
好的，好的，非常感谢
falling and for tuning in we'll see you
下降和调优，我们将看到你
around next time
下一次左右
you
您